[{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>University students _________ behave well.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Can","Should","May","Must"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Gloria&nbsp;_______ have finished the project two days ago.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Must","May","Can","Supposed to"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>You are Goodluck, ___?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are you?","Aren\u2019t you?","Are\u2019nt you?","Don\u2019t you?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>He _______ not come now.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Needs","Needed","Need","Will need"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Janet ________ to know that we are all here.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Suppose","Supposes","Is supposed","Should suppose"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Let it be _________ that there was no king in Ayegun.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Know","Knew","Known","Knows"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>We shall see you soon, __ _?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shall we ?","Shan\u2019t we?","Shouldn\u2019t we","Should we"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Neither of the presidential candidates ______ suitable.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are","Is","Is been","Are been suitable."],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Ten miles ____ a great distance.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Is","Are","Is been","Was been"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>If I were the president, I _______ ask for the money.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Will","Should","Would","Can"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>I will see you after I ________ spoken with your supervisor.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Might have","Have","Will have","Would have"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>\u201cYou _______ now see the director\u201d, the secretary told the visitors&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Can","May","Should","Would"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>She isn\u2019t Gloria __ _?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Is she?","Isn\u2019t she?","Aren\u2019t she?","Doesn\u2019t she?"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>We have a bus, _______?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Didn\u2019t we?","Don\u2019t we?","Doesn\u2019t we?","Hasn\u2019t we?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>I knew David ______ let us down.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["May","Will","Might","Can"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>You ________ me last week.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ought to see","Ought to had seen","Ought to have seen","Had to have seen"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Twenty dollars ___ enough for my lunch.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Are","Is","Are just","Was just"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The pests ____ our farm every year.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Invade","Invades","Has invades","Had invades"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>If I were the Governor, I _______ ask for the project.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Will","Should","Would","Can"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>When ______ the Cleric ______ today?&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Does\/arrives","Does\/arrived","Does\/arrive","Do\/arrive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>We shall see you soon, _________?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Shall we?","Shan\u2019t we?","Shouldn\u2019t we","Should we"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>You missed the match, _______?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Don\u2019t you?","Didn\u2019t you?","Hadn\u2019t you?","Doesn\u2019t you?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Walk the dog right now, _______?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Walkn\u2019t you?","Will you?","Shall you?","Would you?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that best completes the gap<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>I am a student, _______?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I\u2019m I?","Aren\u2019t I?","Isn\u2019t I?","Wouldn\u2019t I?"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I heard his supposed apology","I heard his unconvincing apology","I heard his suppose apology","I heard he was supposed apology"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pick out the odd\/wrong expression in each of the following:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["I suppose you know the way","I am supposed you know the way","I suppose he knows the way","They suppose he knows the way"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My friend&rsquo;s parent&rsquo;s are <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">magnanimous <\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Rich and popular","Sociable and lovable","Kind and generous","Wicked and stingy"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>My friend has an <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">overbearing<\/span> attitude toward me. <br><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Patient","Impatient","Opinionated and domineering","Considerate and respectful"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>There are a number of <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">makeshift building&nbsp;<\/span>&nbsp;in town&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Modern buildings","Old fashion buildings","Temporary buildings","Permanent buildings"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Post UME is a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">hurdle to cross<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["A necessary and simple exam to pass","An unnecessary and difficult exam to pass","An unnecessary but simple exam to pass","A necessary and challenging exam to pass"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p style=\"text-align: left;\"><strong>His contribution to the project is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">invaluable<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Extremely useful","Of no value","Of little value","Can not be valued"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>That was a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">down to earth<\/span> approach .<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Poor","Ordinary","Practical","Immodest"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Concerning my admission, I have to <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">cross my fingers<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Wait and hope for the best","Wait in frustration","Wait confidently","Take some risk"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>My father is <u>indifferent<\/u> to my choice of University<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Supports","Opposes","Not decided","Not concerned"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>We need an <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">ad hoc<\/span> arrangement towards the project&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Intelligent","Advanced","Permanent","Temporary"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The student\u2019s reply to the lecturer <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">betrayed<\/span> his rudeness<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Covered","Showed","Reduced","Increased"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>His conduct in the last elections was <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">above board<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Arrogant","Honest","Above average","Excellent"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>That was a <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">dispassionate<\/span> decision&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bias","Personal","impartial","Ineffective"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that most appropriately expresses the idea in the underlined expression.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>On the matter of worship, some <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">sit on the fence<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Go to the extreme","Are decisive","Are fanatics","Are undecided"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the options nearest in meaning to the underlined word or phrase.<\/span><br><\/p><p><b>In this matter, we must be prepared to tolerate human <\/b><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><b><i>frailty<\/i><\/b><\/span><\/p>","options":["inquisitiveness","weakness","profligacy","innovation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p><p><strong> I detest his <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">lackadaisical<\/span> attitude<\/strong><\/p>","options":["careless","lazy","supercilious","disloyal"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Nobody will endure such <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">profligate<\/span> spending habits<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Generous","Arrogant","Wasteful","Mindless"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the options nearest in meaning to the underlined word or phrase.<\/span><br><\/p><p><strong>Is he <i><span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">oblivious<\/span><\/i> of the political situation in his community?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["unconscious","conscious","afraid","intolerant"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that is nearest in meaning to the word underlined:<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>Many people look into the future <\/strong><strong>with <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\"><i>trepidation<\/i><\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["certainty","uncertainty","fear","faith"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the options nearest in meaning to the underlined word or phrase.<\/span><br><\/p><p><strong>Can you marry such a <u><i>lanky <\/i><\/u><u class=\"\"><i>man<\/i> <\/u>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tall and thin","Sturdy","Fat and short","Tall and short"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><span style=\"font-weight: bolder;\">Choose the options nearest in meaning to the underlined word or phrase.<\/span><br><\/p><p><strong>The election system we adopted was his <u><i>brainchild<\/i><\/u><\/strong><\/p>","options":["undoing factor","invention","power","fabrication"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Peter always approaches issues <u>optimistically<\/u><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Realistically","Pessimistically","Carelessly","Unrealistically"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><b>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/b><\/p><p><b>Why should Dixon be <u>evasive<\/u> in answering the question?<\/b><\/p>","options":["Indirect","Direct","Guessing","Sure"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>John and Ahmed\u2019s ideas were <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">speculative<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Stipulative","Superlative","Factual","Attractive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Henry was admitted to the hospital with <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">profuse<\/span> bleeding<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Much","Little","Internal","Continuous"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Many people regard him as <u>prolific<\/u><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Diplomatic","Productive","Unproductive","Unacademic"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Our success is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">paramount<\/span> in his mind<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Unimportant","Important","Certain","Uncertain"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>In all, I consider the behaviour <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">unpalatable<\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Unacceptable","Offensive","Acceptable","Inoffensive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Her action will certainly <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">exacerbate<\/span> the situation<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ameliorate","Worsen","Aggravate","Clarify"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Is he really behaving <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">oddly<\/span>?&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Abnormally","Normally","Evenly","Properly"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>He always approaches issues <u>optimistically<\/u><\/strong><\/p>","options":["Realistically","Pessimistically","Carelessly","Unrealistically"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option opposite in meaning to the word underlined.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Her health <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">deteriorated<\/span> rapidly<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Worsened","Improved","Stagnated","Declined"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sentences is correct?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["One should mind his business","One should mind one\u2019s business","One should mind her business","One should face his business"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following sentences is correct?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A ten year old boy is missing","A ten-year old boy is missing","A ten year-old boy is missing","A ten-year-old boy is missing"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that sounds the same with the given word. <\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Key<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kiss","Quay","Keyed","Kissed"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the option that sounds the same with the given word.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>Two<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tool","Too","Tow","To"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is correctly spelled.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Acomodation","Accommodation","Accomodation","Acommodation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is correctly spelled.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Embarrassment","Embarassment","Embarrasment","Embarasment"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Choose the word that is correctly spelled.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Horrific","Horific","Horiffic","Horriffic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong><u>As soon as Joy arrived, <\/u>she started looking for food.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>expression is an ___________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adverbial phrase of reason","Adverbial clause of reason","Adverbial phrase of time","Adverbial clause of time"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>My friend,<u> a brilliant lecturer<\/u>, won many prizes.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined expression is&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>a(n) _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Adjectival clause","Relative  clause","Appositive phrase","Subject of 'won'"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I passed very well <u>because<\/u> I studied hard.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined expression is a(n) ___________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Relative clause introducer","Linking verb","Adverb of reason","Subordinating conjunction"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><b>Bello and I love <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">each other<\/span><\/b><\/p><p><b>The underlined expression is a(n) ___________<\/b><\/p>","options":["Preposition","Reciprocal pronoun","Noun phrase","Adjectival phrase"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I prefer <u>writing<\/u> to acting.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined expressions is a(n) __________.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Verb","Participle","Gerund","Object"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong><u>Having finished my assignment, <\/u>I started watching television.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined&nbsp;<\/strong><strong>expression is a(n) _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Infinitive clause","Gerund","Participial phrase","Noun clause"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong><u>If you leave early, <\/u>you\u2019ll meet Sola at home.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined expression is a __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nominal clause","Verbal clause","Conditional clause","Adjectival clause"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong><u>Wounded by a lion,<\/u> the hunter trudged home.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined expression is a _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nominal clause","Verbal clause","Participial clause","Adjectival clause"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I\u2019m proud<u> of you<\/u>.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>The underlined expression functions as<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Prepositional complement","Adjectival complement","Subject complement","Verbal complement"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A noun phrase lacks one of the following<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Noun","Verb","Adjective","Adverb"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Eve gave Adam an apple.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong><em>An apple<\/em> in the sentence functions as__________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Subject of the verb \u2018gave\u2019","Direct object of the verb","Indirect object of the verb","Object complement"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>I wonder if you know where he lives.<\/strong><\/p><p><strong>This sentence is a(n) _________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Thoughtful statement","Polite command","Polite command","Subtle exclamation."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An example of gradable adjectives is _______<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Each","Beautiful","Dead","Live"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A clause differs from a phrase because a clause contains __________<\/strong><\/p>","options":["A larger number of words","A fewer number of words","A finite verb","A non- finite verb"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"}]